翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
This brings us to our final clever improvement to the AList class.
这是我们对 AList 类最后一次巧妙的改进
How do turn this horrible--
怎么把可怕的..
I don't know why I said it that way--
我不知道为什么这么说
horrible parabola into this beautiful line.
把可怕的抛物线变成这条美丽的直线
So if we look at this resize method here--
看看这个 resize 方法
sorry, this code right here--
抱歉，这里的代码...
that's our problem.
这是问题所在
Something here is broken.
这里某些东西有问题
And what I want you to do is try and consider how you might fix this.
试着考虑如何解决这个问题
Now, the solution to this problem is actually a bit tricky.
解决这个问题实际上有点棘手
And even after I show you, you might be a little mystified.
即使我演示后，你也可能会有点困惑
And we'll cover the analysis later.
稍后会介绍分析
But why don't what you do is maybe give it a shot.
但你为什么不试一试呢？
Maybe even try out the AList speed test to test your solution.
尝试测试你的 AList 解决方案的速度
And I'll spoil it in a moment.
一会揭晓
So let's actually go back to our speed testing environment,
回到速度测试环境
and let's look at our AList class.
看看 AList
This is our trouble.
这是我们的麻烦
So perhaps you thought, what if I increase the amount by which we resize?
你可能会想，如果增加 resize 的数量怎么样？
Maybe by, I don't know, from 1 to 10.
也许从1改到10
So if I recompile my code and now I do speed test AList,
重新编译，执行速度测试
I'll see it's fast.
很快
It's not as fast as the SLList, but it's pretty fast.
没有 SLList 快，但相当快
And while that seems to be a big improvement,
虽然这似乎是一个很大的进步
there's actually something a little subtle here that's tricky.
实际上这里有些很棘手的微妙的东西
I mean, as subtle things often are.
微妙的事情往往如此
And that's if we increase our speed test AList runtime up to a million,
如果将速度测试运行时间增加到一百万
and now we try running it again,
再试一次
it's quite slow.
相当慢
It should not be like this.
不应该这样
In fact, it's taking quite a long time.
这需要相当长的时间
So even though we increased this size up to 10,
使我们把这个大小增加到10
we were only kind of hiding the problem.
只是在某种程度上隐瞒了问题
There's still a big problem here.
大问题仍然存在
So there's actually a bigger, better solution,
实际上有一个更好的解决方案
which is rather than adding 10, I'm going to multiply by some number.
不是加10，而是乘以某个数字
Let's say two.
比如2
So let's try now by multiplying the size of our array.
现在乘以数组的大小来试试
If we try running it, it's quite fast.
运行，相当快
Look how fast it is.
看看多快
In fact, I can crank this thing up to 10 million.
事实上我可以把这玩意儿开到1000万
Try running it again.
再运行一次
It should still be pretty fast.
仍然很快
And that's actually the state-of-the-art approach.
这实际上是最先进的方法
And real lists, like the list inside of Python,
而真正的链表，比如 Python 中的 list
basically uses this multiplicative trick.
基本上就是用这个乘法技巧
So what we have right here.
我们现在有的是
this addLast approach, where we add some random factor or some scaling factor, r-factor, this is unusably bad.
这个 addLast 方法，添加一些随机因素、缩放因素、r 因素，这是非常糟糕的
The resizing factor, if used in an additive way,
使用加法调整大小
it's just not going to work.
这是行不通的
I mean, unless you cheat and you make r-factor super big.
除非你作弊让 r 因子变得超级大
But then that's cheating, because then you just keep around a size billion list.
但那是作弊，因为这样你要维护一个10亿大小的链表
I mean, of course that works.
当然也管用
By contrast, if we actually use a multiplicative or geometric rescaling,
相比之下，使用乘法或几何重定比例
then we get great performance.
就会有很好的表现
This is wonderful.
这太棒了
This is how all kinds of lists out there are implemented.
这就是各种链表的实现方式
But we can't do the analysis yet.
但我们还不能做分析
We're going to wait till after the midterm to go into detail.
等到期中考试后再详细讨论
So for now, we'll treat it as some kind of wizard magic that this is the right approach.
现在把它当作某种巫术，看作是正确的方法
Now, there's still a little bit more we want to do,
现在还有更多的事情要做
which is that occasionally, we'll have an issue where our list gets super big.
偶尔遇到的问题使链表变得超级大
It goes up to a billion items.
大到10亿项
And then we remove 999 million items.
然后删掉9.99亿项
So at that point, we're only using 1% of our available-- of our array, and that's wasteful, right?
此时我们只使用了可用数组的1%，这是浪费对吧？
I mean, we could always make a list fast that uses an array by keeping a giant array,
我们可以通过维持一个巨大的数组来使链表更快
but that's just a waste of space.
但有点浪费空间
And so the question is what do we actually want to do to make this better?
问题是我们究竟要做什么来使之更好？
I kind of spoiled that problem.
我有点破坏这个问题了
OK, that's fine.
好的
So what can we do to make it better?
怎么让它变得更好？
Well, often what we'll say is an array list has a usage ratio, you might call it, or a load factor.
通常数组链表有一个使用率，你可以称之负载因子
And that's simply the size of the array divided by the length of the-- sorry,
这就是数组的大小除以...抱歉
the size of the list divided by the length of the array that represents the list.
链表的大小除以它代表的数组的长度
So often what you'll do is if the load factor, that usage ratio, falls below 25%,
通常你会做的是，如果负载率，即使用率，降到25%以下
then you'll half the array size.
数组大小将减半
And we'll do some more details on this in a few weeks.
我们将在几周内详细对比
So just as an example, let's say we have here an array that it has length 100, but the list is only size four.
举个例子，假设这里有一个长度为100的数组，但链表大小只有4
So the usage ratio here is only 4%.
所以使用率只有4%
That is well less than 25%, so this should have been resized at some point.
远远不到25%，应该在某个时候进行调整
And so this actually drives home a really important trade-off between time and space efficiency.
这实际上促使人们在时间和空间效率之间进行了非常重要的权衡
We'll see this over and over again.
我们会一遍又一遍地看到这点
We'll talk about things like hash tables and how we can exploit space to save time.
我们将讨论哈希表等内容，以及如何利用空间来节省时间
That will be a big theme of course.
这将是一个很大的主题
So with that, we have now built basically an array list.
至此，我们基本上构建了一个数组链表
We have to do a little bit more tweaking,
还需要做更多的调整
but that's the core idea, the most important stuff.
但这是核心思想，也是最重要的东西
And with this next little video, you'll be ready to finish project 1A.
看了下段小视频，你就可以完成项目1A 了
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）